# VICTOR WILLIAMS

Full Stack Developer

444 N 4th Street, 401 Philadelphia, PA 19123 484-895-5489 vaporjawn.github.io/

vrwilliams719@gmail.com

### **OBJECTIVE**

Freelance software developer with strong analytical skills and proficiency in mathematics. Individual with ability to follow established procedures and work under little or no supervision. Bringing expertise in writing full-stack code to support multiple platforms, including web, android, and iOS, and a solid grasp of data structures and object- oriented designs.

#### EDUCATION

## Temple University,

Philadelphia, PA May 2019

- Bachelor of Arts: Computer Science and Criminal Justice Certificate: Computer Security
- Studied the subjects of Discrete Mathematics,
   Differential Calculus, Data Structures, Algorithms, and Operating Systems within the Computer Science Curriculum.

#### ACTIVITIES -

Temple University
Development Team – Eboard,
Computer Science Tutor (TU),
(ACM) Association for
Computing Machinery,
Scrum Alliance,
(MLH) Major League Hacking,
PennApps at UPenn,
Alliance for Minority
Participation in STEM.
The Odyssey Online,
Let's Get Ready SAT Prep

Program,

Owlchestra, Violinist

## EXPERIENCE

#### BankMobile

Software Engineer

Mar. 2020 – Present

- Architecture and development of REST services powered web-based SaaS application
- Web, iOS, and Android applications
- A hand in both web and mobile development
- · Collaborated on a large scale of developers based around the globe
- Skills: Xamarin, Angular.JS, C#, RESTfulAPI, Azure, SQL, Swift, JavaScript, JSON

#### **AmeriCorps**

Aug. 2019 - Feb. 2020

Information Technology Manager

- Refined and improved the existing documentation within the system
- Reduced number of open tickets by 87% by prioritizing all open issues
- Updated several School District websites from AngularJS to ReactJS
- Managed a tech team and all technology in Taggart John H. School
- Skills: Angular.JS, API, Cloud, JSON, HTML5, CSS, Vue, MongoDB

BitGamer Nov. 2018 – Nov. 2019

Full Stack Developer / Tournament Organizer

- Developed a tournament hosting web application along with a small team
- · Lead a geographically distributed team with large and small scale projects
- Wrote a series of technical documents to ehlp speed up new engineer onboarding
- Managed social media for the company and performed quality analysis
- Skills: React.js, Node.js, RESTfulAPI, AWS, Java, Python, HTML5

#### CrystalFruit

Dec. 2016 - July 2018

Full Stack Developer

- Implemented solutions using Agile (SCRUM) methodology
- Developed full-stack web applications which processed, analyzed, and rendered data
- Maintained and updated websites upon request per client
- Planned, wrote, and debugged web applications and software
- Skills: Bootstrap, Vue.js, MongoDB, Git, API, PHP, Vue, Ruby, HTML5, CSS, Go, Node.is, JSON